护工的主要工作
Being a carer is all about...
就是认可以及
.acknowledging and,
维护住户的尊严
you know, preserving the residents' dignity.
有人告诉我以前有人跟我说
You know, I've been told, I've been told before
我很擅长安抚人
that l'm very good at making people feel comfortable.
非常擅长我很会社交
Very, you know, I'm very social,
非常会社交 还讨人喜欢
very sociable person, very personable,
很讨人喜欢
very personable...
..very personable.
喜欢笑喜欢去 喜欢
Like to have a laugh, like to go...like to have a
别说你喜欢笑
Don't say you like have a laugh.
她又不是你朋友
She's not your mate.
一你好嗨我是莎拉 贝恩 来面试的
- Hello... - Hi. I'm Sarah Bain. I'm here for the interview.
往里走亲爱的
It's just down there, love.
打扰一下我来找斯蒂夫
Excuse me, l'm looking for Steve.
跟我走快点
Follow me. Be quick.
我们很荣幸
We've been given the honour
为求职者倒杯茶
of getting tea and that for the candidate.
你是唯一一个求职者
You're the only candidate.
麻烦给我杯茶
Er, tea, please, yeah.
谢谢
Та.
加奶加糖吗 -一勺半
- Milk and sugar? - One and a half, please.
-你是说两个都要 -不她是说一句半
- You mean two. - No, she means one and a half.
不是指数字对吧
That's not a number, is it?
0. 就是数字一勺半
Well, it is a number, it's one and a half.
抱歉他很无礼
I'm sorry. He's rude.
顺便介绍下我叫托尼
I'm Tony, by the way.
他叫肯尼
He's Kenny.
和肯尼。达格利什同名
After Kenny Dalglish, easy.
他的名字取自一个送奶工
Where he's named after milkman
以前和他妈妈一起玩多米诺骨牌的那个
his mum used to play dominoes with.
问他多大了
Ask him how old he is,
问他达格利什首次亮相是什么时候
ask him when Dalglish made his debut.
我爸爸是个算命先生
My dad was a fortune teller.
-对我来说 傻蛋
- A point to me.... - Tit.
莎拉 对吧
Sarah, is it?
你为什么会选择来疗养院工作
So what brings you to residential care?
我已经取得了
Well, I've got me Level 1
成人社会护理准备工作一级证书
in Preparing to Work in Adult Social Care.....
我要打断你一下
Going to stop you there.
这个工作需要维护他人的尊严
This job is about treating people with dignity.
-当然-我们的工作场所是他们的家
- Of course. - This is their home that we work in.
所以我不想找个
So l'm not just employing any old
只会擦屁股的麻烦精
knobby-knob stopper to wipe an ass.
我哪里惹到你了吗
Have I upset you?
你发了简历你的技能跟开玩笑一样
You sent your CV and, well, your skills are joking
工作经历也没好到哪里去
and your work's not much better.
我只是还没找到合适的
You know, I just...I haven't found a good fit,
我觉得如果有机会
and I think, given the opportunity...
你以为学习53个小时拿到一级证书
You think 53 hours of your Level 1
就能胜任这份工作了吗
makes you ready for this?
-我没这个意思-让你开啤酒你肯定行
Did I say that? - Cos you might be trusted to pull a pint,
但是照料一个连叉子是什么都搞不懂
but sitting with a scared old man while he's trying to work out
还受了惊吓的老人 -行了艾伦。休格
- what a fork is... - All right, Alan Sugar!
你看清了我我也看清了你
Yeah, you see me, but I ee you as well.
你知道有多少人-你进来的时候就肯定
ame in here absolutely certain... - Do you know how many peof
有宝贵的一级证书我是在浪费你尔时间
- with this precious Level 1... - I was a waste of time.
干一周就坚持不下去了
And they last no more than 1 week.
我连一周都坚持不到
Well, I won't even last that long.
做好你的工作吧
Stick your job.
你知道吗我爷爷得了阿兹海默症
Do you know, me grandad had Alzheimer's
我那时还小但是我记得
and I was only young, but I remember...
"也许就不会觉得自己这么差动了”
"maybe l'll feel less like shit."
所以我理解尊严的含义
Sol understand dignity.
但通过你和人交谈的方式来看
But from the way that you've carried on,
我不确定你理解这个词
I'm not sure that you do.
你能于得不错
You'll do fine.
-周一来上班吧-无所谓了
- You can start Monday.... - Whatever.
我是故意激怒你的
I was baiting you.
停一下
Stop!
你要的茶
You wanted tea.
我不应该在无人监管的情况下出来
I'm not supposed to be out here unsupervised,
但是我知道了大门的密码
but I learnt the door code
我记了下来
and I wrote it down.
好吧-他们估计要改密码了
- OK.... - They'll change the code now.
没关系我原意冒这个险
That's all right. I'll risk that.
因为我喜欢你
Cos I like you.
我的天
Fucking hell.
托尼
Tony!
托尼过来伙计
Tony, come on, lad.
进来
In!
谢谢
Ta-ra.
星期一见
I'll see you Monday.
怎么样
So?
-看看你-嚷嚷什么
- Look at you! - What's that screaming?
她找到工作了鲍勃
She got the job, Bob.
估计干个五分钟就搞砸了
l'll give her five minutes before she fucks it...
鲍勃别这样
Bob, don't.
IL
我话放在这你也是这么想的
I say it, you think it.
我不会搞砸的这次肯定不会
I won't mess up, not this time.
一你开车了-对啊
- Did you take the car? - Yeah.
她今天把车开走了 明明轮到我了
well, She took the car today. It's my turn....
她有面试
Well, she had her interview.
那也不能把我钥匙拿走-我出钱买的车
- Doesn't mean she can take my keys. - I paid for the car.
车是全家人的又添乱了 对吧
Car's for all the family. Messed up there, didn't you?
那你今天干什么了 爸爸
And what did you do today, Dad, eh?
-挠右蛋还是左蛋-我太了解你了
- Did
d you scratch your right bollock or left? -I see you...
虽然你妈不了解
..even if she doesn't.
哈喽亲爱的今天过得不开心吗
Hello, love. You having a sad day?
西尔玛
Thelma?
你还好吗 要去哪
Are you all right? Where are you going?
没有你的
You get nothing.
我能不知道吗
Don't I know?
-比尔是在送信不好意思 -好
- Bill's just delivering the post, if you'll excuse us? - Yeah.
-没有她的信-对 亲爱的 还没到呢
- Nothing for her.... - No, love, not yet.
有我的信吗比尔
Any for me,
Bill?
应该是没有了
l'll take that as a no.
跟我来办公室吧
Follow me to the office, please.
我们这要先进行一周的入职培训
So what we have here is a one week induction...
还有两天的实践训练
..with two days training on the floor.
试用期六个星期我会尽力帮你的
The first six weeks of probationary but l'll do my best by you.
夜班的时候他们通常都没事
Nights, you know, they're generally OK.
我换了班这样就能给你做入职培训
I've switched my shifts so I can be doing your induction,
把工作交代清楚
so it's all joined up.
对了还有制服
Right, uniform.
我妈妈选的颜色
Me mum chose the colour.
-这些以前都是她的 -好的
- Used to be hers, all this.... - OK.
这衣服让人感觉是在零食店上班
I think it makes it look like you work in a tuck shop
《玩乐学校》或者现在孩子看的烂剧里白
or on Play School or whatever shit they watch these days,
我没孩子
I haven't got kids.
你先换衣服吧 然后
l'll let you get changed, then, and
等下我回来 带你参观一下
when I come back, give you the guided tour,
说一下注意事项
lay out a few don'ts and do's.
我要用电话我得打个电话 -好的
I need the phone.... - Oh, eh! -I need the phone.... - Yeah, yeah
可以进来了
Yeah, you're OK.
警官
Er, police.
你好我叫斯蒂夫,弗罗比舍
Hello, my name's Steve Frobisher.
这里是晴空疗养院
I'm calling from Bright Sky Care Home.
我们有一位住户失踪了
One of our residents has gone missing.
他叫托尼。康奈尔
His name is Tony Connell.
47岁
He's 47 years old.
患有早期阿兹海默症
He has young onset Alzheimer's.
身穿牛仔裤和蓝色夹克
Jeans and a blue jacket, I think.
下午茶的时候他就不见了
Well, he hasn't been seen since tea.
谢谢你好吧
Yeah, thank you. All right.
打这个电话就会有人接
Well, someone will be here to answer this number.
好的谢谢好谢射谢 再见
OK, thank you. OK, thank you. Bye.
你现在跟我走
You with me now...
一但是-快点
- But... - Come on.
我知道他可能在哪 估计去他妈妈家了
I know where he'll probably be, he'll have gone to his mum's.
你能搞定吗 她得跟我走
Have you got this? Cos I need her with me.
这里只剩两个护エ了 逗我呢吧
Well, there's only two of us. Are you kidding?
我们去去就回
We'll be quick.
我的脚疼
My feet hurt.
这是因为你一整天都在
Oh, that's because you've been walking over
我心上徜祥 朋友
my heart all day, pal.
来我们坐下休息一会
Come on, let's have a sit-down.
你会通过她的脚
You'll know her...
认出她来
.by her foot
最小巧的藤黄色的手
The smallest gamboge hand
连着手指 也是指尖间的所在
Fingers where the toes should be
会更多地冒犯沙子
Would more affront the sand.
真美
That's beautiful.
这是他离开的路线
This is his route.
我没法分心找他 你两边都看看
I can't watch for him, you can, both windows.
你还记得他的长相吧
You remember his face, right?
他年纪也不算大 怎么这么严重了
He's a bit young, isn't he, for all this?
这种情况比你想象的要常见
It happens more than you think, you know.
他得阿兹海默症估计有一阵子了
Probably been ill for a while with the Alzheimer's,
但他妈妈一直瞒着他
but his mum was masking it.
总之 她死了 他在后厨放了火
Anyway, she dies and he sets fire to the back kitchen,
-最后半裸地走在街上 -天呐
- ends up walking down the street half naked... - Shit.
警察把他抓住的时候 他一直说
Police pick him up and he's like,
"别碰我 别碰我"
"Don't touch me, don't touch me!"
-你了解这种情况吧 -不了解
- You know the sort of thing? - No.
经过几次评估
A few evaluations later
和一两次脑部扫描后 他就住到疗养院了
and a brain scan or two and he moves in with us.
他人不错
He's a lovely fellow...
但不管怎样他都会乱跑
...but can't keep him still for love nor money.
那里
There.
他在那儿
There he is.
-在那 -好样的
- There... - Good girl, good girl.
托尼过来伙计
Tony, come on, mate.
托尼托尼
Tony! Tony!
过来-我要回去找我妈
- Come on... - Going back to me ma.
托尼过来兄弟
Tony, come on, mate...
把你该死的手拿开行吗
Get your fucking hands off me, will ya?!
好了托尼你会像上次那样
Tony, come on. You're going to get me into trouble
让我在警察那难以交代的
with the police again like last time.
一你他妈是谁啊这么跟我讲话-托尼
- Who the fuck are you to talk to me like that? - Tony...
-你现在糊涂了伙计 -想打一架吗
- You're just confused, mate. - Do you want to go?
知这样我是斯蒂夫 -我还以为你会欢迎
- Come on. It's only Steve. - I was expecting a big hello here
但你却这么对我
and this is what you do.
一句半的糖
One and a half sugars.
我要回去找我老妈
I've got to get back to me ma.
她需要我
She needs me.
我不在家的话她会担心
She worries about me when l'm not there.
为什么 是因为你上学的时候调皮捣蛋吗
Why, were you a naughty boy at school, was you?
有时是的
Sometimes, yeah...
那她确实该担心对吧
she had a right to worry, then, didn't she?
你想去我们家吗
Well, do you want to come back to ours?
我老妈做的炖杂烩全世界最好吃
Me ma makes the best scouse in the world.
我也爱炖杂烩 尤其是配上一大句棕酱
Oh, I love scouse, especially with a load of HP.
你能把她的秘方给我吗
Can you tell me her recipe?
不行她死也不会给你的
No, she'd rather die.
她去世了 对吧
She is dead, isn't she?
我忘了我老妈去世了
I forgot me ma was dead.
托尼我们带你回家
We're going to take you home, Tony.
我要回家
I'm going home...
托尼现在有别人住在那
Somebody else lives there now, Tony.
市议会已经把房子给别人了
The council, they've given that to someone else.
你现在住在我们那
You have a bed in a home with us
晴空疗养院你还记得吗
Bright Sky Homes, do you remember?
晴空
Bright Sky.
我墙上有海报
Poster on me wall.
布鲁斯。格罗贝拉阿兰。肯尼迪
Bruce Grobbelaar, Alan Kennedy...
菲尔。尼尔
.Phil Neal...
马克。劳伦森阿兰。汉森
Mark Lawrenson, Alan Hansen,
声米。李罗尼。惠兰克雷格。约翰斯屯
Sammy Lee, Ronnie Whelan, Craig Johnston...
伊恩。拉什肯尼。达格利什
.lan Rush, Kenny Dalglish...
格雷姆。索内斯
..Graeme Souness...
索内斯是员猛将 对吧
Fierce player, Souness, wasn't he? Yeah.
他是我最爱的球员
He was me favourite.
来吧 托尼
Come on, Tony.
带我看看你的海报
Hey, come and show me your poster.
-还好吗 -嗨
- You all right? - Oh, hey.
还有六份早餐没做 也还没来得及喂饭
So, we've got six breakfasts due, and we're behind on feeds.
怎么会没按时给他们喂饭
How did we get behind on feeds?
要帮忙备药就返迟了
Needed a hand with the meds order. We're behind.
老年人起迟了我们也迟了
Seniors are behind, we're behind.
你要不要先换格洛丽亚的垫子
Do you want to make a start on Gloria's pad change?
然后给赫尔克里斯喂早饭
Then lead on to Hercules' breakfast?
好吧 要我来换垫子吗
Oh, yeah, I get pads, do 1?
怎么你觉得她会让我来换吗
What, you think she'll let me do it?
好了该下楼了
OK, time for downstairs.
我知道
I know.
我喜欢调皮殿子好吧
- I like naughty.. - OK.
有个小男孩叫利亚姆
Now, there's this little boy called Liam,
他半夜下楼
and he goes downstairs in the middle of the night
跟他爸要了一杯水
and he asks his dad for a cup of water...
他们确实会那样做
Oh, they do that.
他爸爸说"天响利亚姆这是你今晚
And his dad says, "Jesus, Liam, that's the 15th one"
他爸爸说"天呐利亚姆 这是你今晚
要的第15杯水了"
"you've asked for tonight."
小孩不睡觉的时候确实麻烦
Oh, it's difficult when they won't asleep.
他说爸爸我知道这是第15杯水"
And he says, "I know it's the 15th, Dad,"
但我的房间还是在着火"
"but me room's still on fire."
这笑话不好笑
It's not a great joke.
你准备好和我下楼了吗
Are you ready for me to start downstairs now?
-有一个小男孩叫利亚姆 -是的
- There's this little boy called Liam... - Yes.
他半夜下楼
.and he goes downstairs in the middle of the night,
跟他爸要一杯水
and he asks his dad for a cup of water.
赫尔克里斯
OK, Hercules.
在吃早饭前要先装上牙齿
I need you to pop your teeth in before we do breakfast.
你不喜欢我这么做
You don't like me doing it.
上次你咬了我 还记得吗
You bit me last time. Do you remember?
来赫尔克吃饭前..。
Come on, Herc, before we...
来赫尔克吃饭前.。
来赫尔克吃饭前..
Come on, Herc, before we...
真他妈的
Fuck's sake...!
什么 你在指什么呢
What? What are you pointing at?
什么 我的头发吗
What? Me hair?
头发怎么了
What about it?
我的心就是我的王国
My mind to me a
kingdom is,
在其中我找到诸多欢愉
therein such present joys I find,
世界所能给予的和在此之上滋长的
that it excels all other bliss that Earth affords
都不及此
or grows by kind.
我所求诸多 世人皆有
Through much I want that most do have,
但我的心不允乞求
yet still my mind forbids to crave.
没有王子的气派 没有富人的积蓄
No princely pomp, no wealthy store,
没有获胜的力量
no force to win the victory,
RI
没有减轻伤痛的狡黠头脑
no wily wit to salve a sore,
没有模型来勾勒一双爱眼
no shape to feed a loving eye.
我不曾像奴隶一般屈服于此种种
To none of these I yield as thrall.
ints
For why?
为什么
因为一切由我的心提供
My mind doth serve for all.
我时常看到过度饮食者
I see how plenty surfeits oft,
也看到心急的攀登者很快跌落
and hasty climbers soon do fall.
我看到这些高高在上者
I see those that are aloft,
厄运也会萌荫其上
mischance may threaten most of all.
他们辛辛苦苦劳作战战兢兢坚持
They get with toil, they keep with fear.
我心无法承受此虑
Such cares my mind could never bear.
随遇而安为吾信条
Content I live, this is my stay...
她是英语老师
English teacher.
他们总让大家上圣诞节的班
They always tell people to take the Christmas shift.
不仅工资更高 还能收获快乐
Not only is the pay better, but you actually have a good time.
真好
It's nice.
出于某种原因
And for some reason,
圣诞节很少有人失禁
at Christmas less people shit themselves.
这要感谢圣诞老人-没错
- Thank Santa for that. - Yeah.
瞧啊因此我像王者一样欢跃
Lo, thus I triumph like a king,
满足于我的心所赋予的一切
content with what my mind doth bring.
、这首诗真优美波莉
That was beautiful, Polly.
什么我说讲得真优美小波
- What? -I said, that was beautiful, Pol.
有位从兰开夏郡来的年轻淑女
That was a young lady from Lancashire,
她抵挡不住情人的情欲
who succumbed to her lover's desire.
她说"这是罪过但既然进去了
She said, "Oh, this is sin, but now that it's in,
你能再深入一点吗"
can you push it a few inches higher?"
这是我们一起去沙滩时拍的照片
This is you and me when we went to the beach.
走开
Get away!
-爸爸 没事的 -走开
- Dad, it's OK. - Go on, go on...
离我远点
Get away from me.
爸爸是我啊 琼 没事的
Dad, it's me, Joan. It's OK.
走开
Go....
赫尔克
Herc?
-好冷静点朋友 -让她离我远点
- OK, calm down, mate. - Just get her away from me.
-拜托爸爸 没事的 -你没事的没事的
- Please, Dad, it's OK. - You're all right. It's all right.
-把她带走带走 -这是琼是你女儿
- Take her away, take her away. - It's Joan, it's your girl...
她因为过度悲痛丧失了心智
She was out of her mind with grief,
还背负着罪过 天主教的罪过
and guilt, Catholic guilt...
这很古怪但我只觉得她与罪过共生
It was all weird. But I just think she lived with the guilt.
没有访客吗
No visitors?
|| 别这么说
Well, don't say that.
本我 自我和超我都在这已经很挤了
It's crowded enough in here with just me, myself and I.
你要回家了吗
You off home?
等会儿吧
In a bit.
你会玩笨蛋纸牌吗
Do you know how to play Shithead?
什么
What?
很简单的游戏 真的
It's a simple game, really.
发六张牌 三张朝下 三张朝上
You deal three card blind, three cards facing,
++120
你手里再拿三张牌
and you get three cards in your hand.
游戏的目标是把牌都出了
Right, the aim of the game is to get rid of all your cards.
-明白了吗 -明白
- Yeah? - OK.
牌最大的获胜
Highest card wins.
如果你压不过就从牌堆里拿一张
If you can't go higher, then you pick up from the pile.
只有二是不一样的
Only cards that'll do you different is two
出了二或七 就要从头开始
which means you start again from two or seven.
如果我出七你就得出比它小的
If I play a seven, you have to play lower then.
或者出十
Or a ten,
十就类似魔术卡可以清理所有牌
which is like a magic card, a ten clears the whole pile.
-懂了吗 -这么多规则你怎么记住的
- Capishe? - How do you remember all of that?
没关系玩着玩着就会了
It's all right. Yeah, we'll pick up as we go along.
我从来不热衷于
•..
I never was a big fan of...
M-下想不起来了
It'll come to me.
是圣诞节
Christmas.
你为什么不喜欢圣诞节
Well, why weren't you a fan?
爸爸离开的时候就只剩我和特丽莎阿姨
Well, when my dad left, it was just me and Aunt Trisha.
我们得照顾我妈
We had to look after me mum.
太难了
That was hard.
有些时候真的是一团糟
Some days it was really messy.
医生给她开了药之后 她就
And then after that doctor gave her her tablets, then...
一直窝在沙发上
she never left the couch.
我记得有一次圣诞爸爸什么都没给我
I remember one Christmas me Dad didn't get me anything.
没有礼物
No presents.
他说“我跟她说过了"
He says, "I told her"
如果她不当个乖孩子 就什么都没有"
"if she weren't a good girl, she weren't going to get shit."
你是吗
And were you?
是乖孩子吗
Was you a good girl?
当时我在PRU 所以
Well, I was in PRU at the time, so...
PRU是小学生转送部
Oh, it's a pupil referral unit.
基本上没有学校要的孩子才会去那里
It's...it's basically where they put kids no school wants.
别笑那时候我オ12岁
No! But I was 12!
你明自我的意思吗我那时
Do you know what I mean? I was...
认为所有12岁的孩子都应该有礼物不是
I think all 12-year-olds should get presents. Don't you?
是是吧最糟糕的是
- Yeah.... - Yeah, well, the worst thing
我妈还没有异议
was me mum went along with it.
她也一样坏
She's just as bad.
所以你是个十足的坏女孩
So you were a proper bad girl, then?
"十足的坏女孩"
"Proper bad girl."
我确实搞了些破坏
I did some damage.
小学的时候
Primary school,
我弄丢了弹弹球老师也找不到
I'd lost me bouncy ball, and the teacher couldn't find it,
所以我就弄碎了教室里所有的灯
so I smashed every single light in the classroom
被停了两周课
and got suspended for two weeks.
学校舞会上索尼娅。夏贝特
Oh, school disco, Sonia Sherbet.
她叫我荡妇
Well, she called me a slag
因为我比她先长出胸
because I had boobs before her.
我就痛打了她一顿
So l broke her nose.
没错我因此转学了
Yeah. Got moved schools for that.
普通中等教育证书考试 考数学的时候
GCSE, Maths.
我去晚了跟老师说我没带
I turned up late and I told my teacher I didn't have me...
计算器 尺子还有我的..
me calculator, me ruler, and me,
-笔-笔对对
- Pen.... - Pen, yeah, yeah.
他对我说我来得太晚
So, so he said to me I was too late
他已经都发完了我就把他打晕了
and he'd given them all out, so...I knocked him out.
-不过我没拿到证书 -我也没拿到
- I didn't get no GCSE though. - Neither did I.
第三所学校找到了我
Third school they found me,
我记得我偷了看门人的钥匙
I remember nicking the keys off the caretaker,
T让我的那些朋友进去
and I let these mates of mine in...
他们把能找到的电脑都格式化了
and they cleared out every computer they could find.
他们不知道是我干的
Yeah. They didn't know it was me.
-否则我可能会被送走 -是啊
Otherwise I probably would've been sent away.... - Yeah.
但我觉得看护员是知道的
But I think the caretaker knew,
但他什么都没说 因为
but he didn't say anything, because...
那时候我朋友在给他口交
Well, I mean, me mate was sucking him off at the time.
-不是吧 -真的
- Fuck...! - Yeah.
你赢了
You win.
我现在倒是后悔做那些事了
Oh, I regret it all now.
我们要玩什么来着
What we playing?
笨蛋纸牌
Shithead.
对
Yeah.
很简单的游戏 真的
A simple game, really.
发六张牌 三张朝下
You deal three cards blind,
三张朝上
then three cards facing,
你手里再拿三张牌
then three cards in your hand.
个游戏的目标是打完你的所有牌明白了
Then the aim of the game is to clear all your cards, yeah?
嗯我知道
Yeah, I know.
你回来晚了
You're home late.
错过了一顿大餐
Hey, you missed a good one.
那边还有好多要洗的餐具
There's loads still to be cleaned there.
你妈提早上床睡觉了
Your mam went to bed early.
说是头疼什么的
Headache or something.
那儿的老人们怎么样
How were the old people?
挺好的
Uh, really good.
嗯
Yeah.
我能间到你身上的老人味 小心点
I can smell them on you. Careful of that.
钠粉和尿味
Sodium powder and piss.
我爸以前就是这个味道
That's what me dad smells of.
我身上的味道应该还好爸爸
I think I smell fine, Dad.
他们那还需要其他人手吗
Do they need anyone else there?
-他们还要人吗 -闭嘴吧
- Do they need anyone? - Oh, fuck off.
你得能抬得动那些老人
You need to be able to lift them.
你的背不好干不了的
You know, and with your back...
食品赈济处
•..
You know, the food banks...
他们今年发放圣诞饼干来着
.they gave Christmas crackers this year.
还他妈很自豪一样
Bloody proud of them they were, too.
90喜欢这些饼干吧 真好"
"You like these crackers, don't you?" "Nice."
+15
祝他们圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas to them.
BBC广播五台直播
This is BBC Radio 5 Live.
早上好现在是3月5日 周四6点36分
Good morning, it's 6:36, it's Thursday, March 5.
一位70多岁的女士在检测出新冠阳性后
A woman in her 70s has become the first person in the UK
成为英国第一例死亡病例
to die after testing positive for coronavirus.
雷丁镇的皇家巴克希尔医院声称
The Royal Berkshire Hospital, in Reading,
她本身患有基础疾病
said she had underlying health issues.
英国的感染人数
The number of people infected in the UK
又升至116人
has jumped again to 116...
羊儿的秘密是它们会轻易爱上人类
Now, the secret with sheep is that they love easily,
一只羊爱上你的方法之一就是给它好吃
and a way to make a sheep love you is to feed it.
这边我的同事苏珊
So, my colleague there, Susan,
她会给你们分发饲料
she's coming round with some feed to give you.
以愿意喂羊的人准备好得到羊羊的爱!
So those of you who are willing, get ready to be loved.
我看你挺乐意的兄弟
I can see you are, fella.
你跟它们一样在吃东西呢
You're chomping at the bit like these are, aren't you?
好了
All right.
准备好 三 二 -
Get ready. Three, two, one.
准备好 三 二
准备好三二一
Get ready. Three, two, one.
去吧传播点爱对了直接过去
Go on! Spread some love. That's it, straight in there.
去吧传播点爱对了 直接过去
朋友们那边那只大的叫晃晃
That big one there, love, is Wonky.
别亲它 它会嫌弃你的
Don't kiss him. He knows where you've been.
我能感受到它的心跳
I can feel her heart.
是吗
Can you?
很平静
Very calming.
你愿意的话可以给它念首诗
You can tell her a poem, if you like.
不了 这样就很好
No, this is nice as it is.
挠挠它的下巴它可喜欢了跟我一一样
Tickle him under his chin, he loves that, like me.
医院给我们来了通知
We've had word from the hospital,
我们要再接收几个老人
we're going to be taking on a few more residents.
多少 -八个
- How many? - Eight.
都是因为新冠病毒
It's the virus thing.
他们就是要给医院腾出空来
They just need, you know, to make space,
摆脱掉一些长期住户
get rid of a few long termers.
-这样安全吗他们是医生亲爱的
- Well, is it safe, like? - They're doctors, love.
怎么你以为我不看新闻吗 我懂
What, and you think I don't watch the news? I know.
这也是我们在尽一份力
This is us doing our bit.
那些老人中大多数几年前就该走了
Most of them should have been out years ago,
他们只是在占用床位
they're just blocking up beds.
我们在发挥作用
We're being useful.
一这是好事 好
- It's good... - OK.
这位是斯坦他85岁了
This is Stan, he's 85 years old.
你好斯坦
Hiya, Stan.
你的口罩呢
Where's your mask?
我不知道需要戴口罩
Uh, I didn't knew we needed to wear them.
-你的主管是谁-我是主管
- Who's your manager? - I'm the manager.
除非接触感染者 否则不用口罩
No masks unless you're around the infection,
他们是这样通知我们的
that's what we were told.
他检测过了对吧 没有感染
He's been tested, right? He's all clear?
那不是我该管的事 送他进去吧
It's above my station, that. Shall we get him in?
我今天还要再送五个人
I've got five others to deliver today.
我们送你去舒服点的地方吧 斯坦
Yeah, let's get you somewhere comfortable, shall we, Stan?
了我要跟你们所有人讲讲新冠相关的规
Right, I need to talk to you all about Covid-19 protocols.
我们需要更多个人防护装备
We need more PPE....
咱们先别说话这么沖好吧
Let's not start out all aggressively, shall we?
我们这个有一点那个有一点
We've got a box of this and a box of that
但主要还是什么都缺
but mostly we've got a box of eff all.
我在努力
Look, I am trying.
我昨天开车去了每个诊所
I drove around every bloody chemist yesterday,
默西塞德郡中心的每家诊所都去了
every one in the best part of Merseyside.
买不到口罩
I couldn't get masks,
买不到酒精棉片什么都没有
I couldn't get alcohol wipes, couldn't get nothing.
公共卫生局也压根不管
And PHE don't give a shit....
对都是定量配给就这么简单
No, it's rationing, pure and simple.
他们想保护NHS至于疗养院
They want to protect the NHS and care homes can just
可以自生自灭
go to hell.
指导意见说只有在距离感染者两米内时
The guidance is face masks should only be worn
才需要戴口罩
when within two metres of the infected
而我们这还没有感染者
and we don't have any infected yet so
所以也不用口罩 好吗
we don't need to wear them, OK?
至于清洁若有疑虑
Cleaning - when in doubt,
就用手边任何消毒剂进行消毒
scrub with every disinfectant you can find.
从现在起住户都將
And residents are to be fed
在自己房间单独用餐
in their rooms exclusively from now on.
我们哪有时间一个个喂饭
Where are we supposed to find time for that?
首要任务是将住户们都隔离开
The priority has to be keeping the residents apart,
所以我们院内
so we have to do a lockdown
必须封闭管理 -但我们在房间之间走动叫
- inside the home. - But we carry it between them.
那我们就要小心
Then we have to be dead careful not
别将病毒四处传播
to carry it between them.
只要发现病例就隔离护理好吗
As soon as we know there's a case, barrier nursing, OK?
勤洗手
Washing hands, erm...
过生日也分开过
Happy Birthday twice,
唱歌的时候也分两段唱
or two verses of Ferry Cross The Mersey.
新口罩新防护围裙呢做不到是吧
New masks, new aprons? Oh, no, we can't do that, can we?
而且禁止探视-什么
- And I'm banning visits. - What?
搞清情况再说
Just till we know.
等下没有这方面要求啊
Hold on, there's no advice on that.
没错这是我要求的
No, that's me.
为了这里每个人的安全我决定这样
I'm saying it's happening, for the sake of everyone here.
比尔怎么办
What about Bill?
他睡在休息室里我拿他怎么办
He sleeps in the lounge. What am I supposed to do with it
让他去自己房间睡一次啊
Tell him to sleep in his own bloody bed for once.
最后一件事
One last thing,
洗衣房说他们现在只能洗
the laundry service have said that they can only do half
之前一半的衣服所以拜托大家
of what they did before so can we please
尽量把被单都用得久一点
try and keep the sheets on the beds a little bit longer.
斯蒂夫得了吧
Oh, Steve, come on.
如果人们生病了就需要新床单
If people are sick they need new sheets.
他们难道不明自吗
Do they not know that?
因为新冠政策 洗衣房的员工也要保持
It's Covid protocol. It's there to keep their staff apart. It's.
我不知道我也不知道真烦人
I don't know. It's...I don't know. It's annoying.
这些都很频
It's...It's all just annoying.
这響都很频
我们从中开始实行好吗
From midday we implement, O?
-我去给你们找防护装备-好
- And I will find you your PPE. - Yeah
一共有92家疗养院
There have been 92 care homes
都爆发了疫情
where an outbreak has been detected.
我们下一步的目标是增加
One of the things we want to do is to extend the amount
疗养院人群的检测数量以及检测能力
of testing of people in care homes and the ability to test..
你去哪了
Where have you been?
出去了 怎么 要告发我吗
Out. Why? Looking to grass me up are you?
你不能出去
You're not supposed to be going out.
收起你这些废话吧 你不也出去工作:
You can cut the holier than thou crap. You're going to wol
那是因为我应该去工作 我的工作需要
I'm supposed to be in work. I'm needed in work.
是是他们都被传染了 你就会把病毒带[
Yeah, and they've all got it, and you're bringing it here,
-有什么区别吗 -因为
so what's the problem? - Because your
你那些狐朋狗友会传染给你
divvy mates could infect you,
你就会传染给我我就有可能传染给住
which could infect me, which could then infect my resident
别放屁了
It's such shit.
我还年轻 我得让我的生命有意义
I'm young. I need to live my life - do something with it.
可不是嘛你在做让生命有意义的事作
Yeah, you're really doing something with your life, aren't yo
好了好了好了
Hey, hey, hey.
你听起来好像你爸爸
You sound like your dad.
她先嚷嚷的 说我不能出门
It's her, saying Il can't go out.
如果他传染给我 我就会传给老人们
If he infects me and then linfect them.
总会有办法解决的 不是吗
Well, there's a solution to that, isn't there?
别那样看着我
Don't look at me like that.
之前没有你的薪水我们也过得好好的
We've coped without your wage before,
现在也可以
we can cope again.
别这样 我喜欢这份工作妈妈
- Come on now... -I like it, Mum.
实际上我很擅长这份工作
Actually, I'm good at it.
*悄然辞行*
*Steal away*
*悄然辞行去往上天
*Steal away to Jesus*
悄然辞行*
*Steal away*
悄然离开家*
WET
*Steal away home*
VA
WET FLOOR
*短暂相聚 就要别离 *
*I ain't got long...*
肯尼帮我个忙回你自己的房间好
Kenny, can you go back into your room for me, please?
-我会尽快把吃的给你 -我不想吃东
- l'll get you fed as soon as I can. - I don't want to be fed.
我想去看电视-休息室关闭了
-I want to watch telly. - The lounge is closed.
我得把这些晚餐都送出去
I need to get all these dinners out.
回房间里去好吗
Can we get you in here?
我马上去拿你的托盘 把你的饭送过
I'll get your tray and bring it in for you.
-你得让我进去 -现在不允许探视
-I need to come in. - You can't be here right now.
不了解情況的话我不能把我爸留在这
I'm not leaving my dad in there knowing what's going on
我们会把事情都安排好的好吗
We'll sort something out, OK?
我现在就要见他让我们进去
I need to see him now. Let us in.
要不你隔着窗户和他说几句话吧
Maybe you can talk to him through the window.
这样对大家都好
It's for the best for everyone.
但对我来说不够好 斯蒂夫
It's not the best for me, is it, Steve?
-为什么你们不进来 -我们进不去
- Why can't you come in? - We're just not allowed in.
他们有规定不让我们接触你们
They're not allowed to let us near you...
你什么意思
What do you mean?
し不允许我们进去 -以防我们感染了新
- It's not allowed... - In case we catch this silly Covid thing
%3D
-那咱们把窗户打开吧 -不不不行
- Let's open the window, yeah? - No, no, we can't...
-我们不能打开窗户 -为什么不行
- We can't open the window. - Why can't we?
++
No, no, we can't.
不行不能打开
*悄然辞行*
*Steal away*
悄然离开家”
*Steal away home...*
你好啊
Hello.
我今天能出去吗
Can I go out today?
不不可以的
No, I'm afraid not, no.
我受不了了
I can't do this.
我受够这里了 我他妈一点也不想待在
I've had it with being here. I don't fucking want to be here
冷静点 托尼
Calm down, Tony.
你知道该怎么做 深呼吸
You know what we do, take a deep breath...
-托尼我是莎拉-里面没事吧
- Tony, it's Sarah. - Everything OK here?
我是你的朋友我不害怕你
I'm your friend and l'm not scared of you.
斯蒂夫你不用进来
Steve, go away.
过来吧
Come on.
来
做运动了吗
Are you doing your exercises?
我能举起一辆公交车
I can lift a bus, me.
那你有好好吃饭吗
Are you eating?
你又不是我妈
You're not my mother.
这像个什么样子
What does it bloody look like?
ゴ 你衣服都晃見荡荡的了
Well, you've got half of it down your top,
我是说你一定是饿坏了
that's what l'm talking about. You must be starving.
别胡说八道了
You cheeky get.
这是什么
What's this?
我在吸气
I'm breathing in.
他没什么事
He was fine.
只是需要冷静冷静
He just needed calming.
一个好消息 一个坏消息
Good news and bad news.
好消息是
The good news is,
我朋友罗伯给我们拿来了一些防尘回:
my mate Rob the builder has got us some dust masks.
坏消息呢
Bad news?
格洛丽亚开始咳嗽了还发烧了
Gloria's got a cough and a temperature.
蒂姆正在她房间陪她 她还好吧
- Tim is with her in her room. - Is she OK?
暂时还好
For now.
斯蒂夫她密切接触过这里所有的人
Steve, there isn't no-one she hasn't been near.
社区医生说
The GP has
现在已经没有能派遣的人员了
said that there is no-one available to send out right now.
估计等有人的时候也只能视频支援
When they do, they'll just be on a screen.
快速反应小组说帮不上我们什么忙
RRT have told us there's nothing down for us.
连一个护士都派不过来吗
We don't even get a nurse?
公所有能紧急响应的护士
All rapid response nurses available have
都被派到当地医院和公立疗养院了
been sent to local hospitals or LA run care homes.
你知道会变成现在这样吗
Did you know it would be like this?
我怎么知道
How could I?
我遵循了所有的防控建议甚至更严木
I followed all the advice. We did more.
没有人跟我们说过
No-one told us.
没有人
No-one.
我妈妈以前也住在这
My mum was in here too.
也是住户吗 -对一开始感觉挺好的
- As a resident? - Yeah. It felt right.
但并不是
But wrong.
我总是确保亲自动手帮她收拾干净
I always made sure I was the one who cleaned her up,
让她能够有尊严地
you know, gave her her dignity with
面对这里的其他员工
the other members of staff,
他们曾经都是她的雇员 不应该让他们
cos they were her employees and they shouldn't be the on
帮她擦屁股
to have to wash her bottom.
我只是希望这里能..
I just wanted this place to...
我想让这里成为一个适合老人居住的地
I wanted it to be a good place to be.
我拿水过来了如果你想喝水的话
I've got some water. If you want to have a sip,
跟我说就行
just let me know.
来吧 先喝一小口
I tell you what, you can have just a little bit.
有什么需要我的吗 格洛丽亚
How can I help you, Gloria?
我真的很不舒服
I'm quite unwell.
你能叫个医生过来吗
You may have to fetch a doctor.
赫尔克里斯 来亲爱的
Hercules, come on, love.
好了
There you go.
慢点
来慢点 慢点
Come on. OK, OK, OK.
-你做运动了吗 -做了
- Are you doing your exercises? - Yes.
她会好起来吗
Is she going to be OK?
你应该待在房间里
You should be in your room.
我会没事吗
Am I going to be OK?
我保证你会的
I promise you will.
莎拉你在里面吗
Sarah? Are you in here?
赫尔克摔倒了
Herc's tripped over.
天哪 赫尔克
Oh, Herc.
我帮你处理一下好吗
Let's get you cleaned up, shall we?
++
疼死了
Fuckin' hell.
我知道我已经用过五项检测了
I know l've used my five tests.
我们这里到处都是我也不知道该隔离
We've got it everywhere and I don't know who to separate
但你是PAT医院的人 你应该援助我的
But you're PAT. You're supposed to be supporting me.
别耽搁我时间
Don't put me on hold.
你们不准再穿成这样来了
Don't you dare come in here dressed like that again.
我们没人染上一个都没有
We haven't got none of that. Not one of us.
把你的防护用品给我们啊
You could give us your kit, eh?
给我们防护用品啊 你们物资那么多
Give us your kit, you rich gits.
给点啊
Just a few pieces!
给我们点啊
Give us your kit!
琼没来斯蒂夫
Joan hasn't turned up, Steve.
-我打给她吧 -不用 我打过了
- Let me call her. - No, I've called her.
一她没接-行你再撑一两小时
- She's not answering. - OK, you stay on an hour or two.
我有的选吗
Well, I...I don't have a choice, do I?
尔和蒂姆 大家都在14天隔离期 只有我
With you and Tim and everyone else on the 14 days, I-l'm i
我也想来帮忙但我可能传染他们
Look, I wish I could come in and help, but l'd infect them a
行了别咳得这么做作
Oh, all right, don't be dramatic about it!
别逗我笑
Don't make me laugh!
屁眼都疼
Oh, it hurts to buggery.
-托莉呢-她关机了
·Is Tori, er...? - Tori's phone's off.
要是叫她来你知道她家人什么德行白
You know what her fella's like if she gets called in.
那些机构都没消息吗
Is there nothing from the agencies?
我再试试
l'll try.
质量委员会知道就留你一个人的话手
CQC will kill the both of us if it's just you there alone.
真的 我们各自尽力吧
Really. You do your best, and I'll do mine.
有诗听吗 小波
You got a poem for me, Pol?
我拿了点药来
Yeah, well, I've got some pills for you.
要不你吃药我念点词给你听
Well, maybe l'll do a recital while I give you them, eh?
"我想变得富有
"I wanna be rich
坐拥无数钱币"
and I want lots of money.
"我不在乎聪明
"I don't care about clever,
也不在乎有趣"
I don't care about funny."
"我要满柜新衣
"I want loads of clothes,
还要一堆钻石"
and I want fuckloads of diamonds."
"听说人们追逐钻石丢了性命"
"Though I hear people die while they're trying to find them
"我会褪去衣服变得不屑一顾”
"And l'll take my clothes off and it will be shameless."
"人人皆知这是成名的必经之路"
You know, because everyone knows that's how you get fam
"我望向太阳
"I'll look at The Sun
又凝视明镜”
and l'll look in The Mirror."
"我身处正轨
"I'm on the right track.
将迎来胜利”
Yeah, I'm on to a winner."
你会没事的 小波
You're gonna be OK, Pol.
天啊肯尼 你怎么了
Jesus, Kenny, what's going on?!
我要给你测体温 好吗
I'm gonna take your temperature, OK, love?
你发烧了
Oh, you're burning up.
吃两片这个试试
Try and take two of these...
我去给你找医生 好吗
.and then l'm gonna call a doctor, OK?
-嗨 -你好
- Hi. - Hello...
%3D
此急救热线已停用
This emergency line is no longer in operation.
请拨打斯温森街诊所
Please try Swinson Street practice for support.
斯温森街诊所已休息
Swinson Street practice offices are now closed.
我们的工作时间是早上八点至下午六
Our working hours are from 8am to 6pm.
如果咨询新冠相关..
If your call is Covid related...
我找了些人 然后睡着了
Look, I tried a few people, and then I fell asleep.
斯蒂夫 肯尼不太好 我找不到医生
Steve, Kenny's not well, and I can't get a doctor out.
非工作时间的号码试了吗
Have you tried the out of hours number?
没人接
Nothing.
完蛋 没别的选择了 打111
Shite. You've no choice. 111.
只会让我一直等啊
You're just on hold forever.
我在的好吧
Look, I'm here, OK? Er...
随时联系我
Just let me know.
欢迎拨打国家医疗服务111热线
Welcome to NHS 111.
111热线目前
NHS 111 are experiencing
处于高峰繁忙期
an extremely high number of calls at the moment,
可能无法及时接线..
and may not be able to answer immediately...
好了肯尼
OK, Kenny.
ок, Kenny.
来吧
Come here, love.
肯尼我需要你深呼吸 好吗
What I need you to do, Kenny, is to breathe deeply, OK?
对深呼吸
That's it, deep breaths.
好了 没事
OK. OK, love.
就是这样肯尼 深呼吸
That's it, Kenny, deep breaths.
请注意接通当地国家医疗服务的过利
Please be aware that a short pause may follow
可能会出现短暂停顿
as you are connected to your local NHS service.
目前处于高峰繁忙期
re experiencing an extremely high number of calls at the mc
可能无法及时.
and may not be able to answer...
请问需要什么服务
What service do you require, please?
救护车 谢谢
A-Ambulance, please.
++
What's the address of the emergency?
请问地址在哪里
晴空疗养院 邮编L64 9SD
Bright Sky Homes. L64 9SD.
我叫萨拉。贝纳
My name's Sarah Berner
位住户感染了新冠 我需要紧急医疗#
and I need urgent medical assistance for a resident with Cov
-在吗 -病人呼吸怎么样
- Hello? - Is the patient breathing?
很不顺畅
Yeah, his breathing's ragged,
发烧到39.2度了
and he's got a temperature of 39.2.
病人清醒吗
Is the patient alert?
不太清醒
He's delirious.
他的年龄呢
How old is he?
他有呼吸病史吗
Does he have a history of breathing problems?
-病人在咳吗 -一直在咳
- Is the patient coughing? - Continuously.
我给他吃了扑热息痛 但这样肯定不行
Look, I've given him paracetamol, it isn't going to be enoug
你测他的血氧值了吗
Have you been able to take his blood oxygen?
-好有点低了 -对对
- OK. That's low... - Yeah. Yeah.
我知道啊 没人 没人接电话
Yeah, I know! Look, no-one...Nobody's picking up.
111没接 社区医生没接 没人帮我
Not 111, not the GP, nobody's helping me.
抱歉 现在所有救护车都在使用中
Unfortunately, all our ambulances are busy right now,
但我们会尽快赶到的
but we will be there as soon as possible...
如果我不是从疗养院打的电话呢
What if I wasn't calling from a care home?
-什么 -疗养院不重要
- Sorry? - Care homes, they don't matter.
一点也不重要是吧
They don't matter any more, do they?
他需要你 也需要我
Look, he needs you and he needs me,
你不是很在意
and you're not interested.
我们会尽快赶来的
We will be with you as soon as we can.
我先找临床医生,..
Let me talk to a clinician...
他们会说 我们不是优先病人
Yeah, and they're gonna tell you we're not high priority.
陪着他
Stay with him,
让他舒适点 关注他的呼吸情况
make him comfortable and monitor his breathing,
我会尽快给你回电
I'll get back to you as fast as I can.
对不起肯尼
I'm sorry, Kenny.
对不起没有人来
I'm so sorry, no-one's coming.
没有人来
No-one's coming.
肯尼我看过网上的论坛
Kenny, I've seen forums online,
教过我应该怎么做
and it tells me what I need to do.
网上说要让人正面朝下
It says what may help is to move you over onto your front
这叫俯卧可以可以让呼吸畅通点
It's called proning, and it may ease...it may ease your pipe
你能听懂吗
Does that make sense to you?
好 深呼吸
Oh, OK. Deep breaths.
对不起
Oh, I'm sorry...
好了肯尼
ок, Kenny.
没事的
OK.
Three, two, one...
对不起 肯尼
I'm sorry, Kenny.
肯尼 我马上回来
Kenny, I'll be one minute.
-莎拉吗 -对
- Sarah? - Yeah.
我是救护车调度中心的马丁
It's Martin from ambulance control.
一好 -我跟临床医生通过话了
- Yeah... - I've spoken to a clinician.
肯尼对我们来说很重要
Kenny is still a priority to us,
但很遗憾现在没有可调度的救护车
but unfortunately we cannot allocate a vehicle right now
我们会努力争取
We'll try and get one...
去他妈的
Fuck off!
托尼是我
Tony, it's me.
托尼抱歉吵醒你 亲爱的
Tony, I'm sorry to wake you, love.
一怎么了 托尼我需要你看着我
- What? - Tony, I needed to look at me.
怎么了你还好吗
What? Are you OK?
我需要 你的朋友肯尼需要帮助
I need...I need help with your friend Kenny.
但可能会让你陷入危险
But it could put you in danger.
托尼 看着我
Tony, look at me.
我需要你清醒地表示同意
I need you to be able to consent properly to that.
现在几点了
What time is it?
-三点半 -什么 凌晨吗
- It's 3:30... - What, in the morning?
托尼托尼拜托 拜托集中精神
Tony, Tony, please, please, please concentrate.
-看着我-看着呢看着呢
- Look at me. - I'm looking, l'm looking.
你愿意和我一起帮肯尼翻身吗
Will you help me move Kenny onto his front?
什么他块头挺大的对吗
What, is he a big lad, is he?
他是你最好的朋友
Well, he's your best friend.
不是吗 -没错
- Isn't he? - That's right.
托尼 拜托 我需要你的帮助好吗
Tony, please, I need your help, OK?
我相信你愿意帮我
I believe that you would give it...
不管你的精神状态如何
...and whatever your state,
我相信你愿意帮我对吗
I believe that you would give it, OK?
所以你愿意吗 -做什么
- So, will you help me? - To do what?
亲爱的我需要你
OK, love, I need you to...
我需要你从床上起来为什么
-I need you to get out of bed... - What for?
|为我需要你帮我 肯尼需要我们帮他
Because I need your help. Kenny needs our help. OK?
所以我需要你下床越快越好
SoI need you to get out of bed as soon as you can.
我需要你去洗下手
And I need you to wash your hands,
-拜托 -好吧 好吧
- please... - All right, all right.
洗一下手吧
Wash your hands, please.
托尼送点肥皂快点
Tony, with soap, come on.
再差一点
Bit more, yeah?
好的够了
OK, that's enough.
我需要你把这个戴到手上
OK, I need you to put these on your hands.
就是这样
That's it.
把这个戴上好吗
You need this on your face, OK?
我们要去抢银行吗
So, are we robbing a bank?
不我需要你一直戴着不管发生什么
No. I need you to keep them on no matter what.
答应我
Promise me.
你明白我们在干什么吗
Do you understand what we're doing?
我不明白你为什么这样焦急
Well, I don't understand why you're so upset.
抱歉 亲爱的跟着我
I'm sorry, love. OK, follow me.
你明白我们在干什么吗
Do you understand what we're doing?
-我来了肯尼 -肯尼
- Here are, Kenny... - Kenny?
-肯尼-肯尼
- Kenny... - Kenny?
-肯尼状況不太好 -他看起来很糟糕
- Kenny's not very well. - He looks really bad.
他是很糟糕但是你知道
He is really bad, but you know what's
我们的帮助能让他舒服一些
gonna make him feel better is us helping him.
他无法呼吸了
Well, he can't breathe.
知道 亲爱的我们需要将他翻过身来1
I know, love, and we need to roll him over onto his front..
你知道吗 我需要你的力气才能做到
and guess what, I need your strength for that.
一只手放这里
I need one hand here...
...and one hand there.
不要不要太紧托尼
Not too...Not too tight, Tony.
温柔一点
Nice and gentle.
托尼我们动作快点
Tony, we need to move quickly,
因为你不该待在这里
because you shouldn't be in here.
-数到三 -肯尼
- After three... - Kenny...
二三-好
- One, two, three... - OK.
-肯尼-好了 亲爱的
- Kenny? - That's it, love.
一你没事了肯-我们让他舒服点
- You're OK, Ken. - Let's make him nice and comfortable.
没事了 肯尼
Kenny, it's OK.
就是这样
There we go.
好了亲爱的
OK, love.
没事了
It's OK.
-肯你没事了 -肯尼 我们马上回来
- You're OK, Ken... - OK, Kenny, we'll be back in one momer
托尼跟我走
Tony, I need you with me.
过来亲爱的
Come on, love.
快点拜托
Now, please.
没事了 肯
It's OK, Ken.
我们马上回来
We'll be back.
托尼你动作可以稍微快点吗
Tony, can you move a bit quicker?
我需要你洗一下手
I need you to wash your hands.
我的手有点痛-你可以跟我一起洗
- My hands are a bit raw... - No, you can wash them with m
你说什么不不不
- What did you say? - No, no, no, no!
你说什么-不不不
你说什么不不不
·What did you say? - No, no, no, no!
- What did you say? - No, no, no, no!
别碰口罩干吗
- Don't touch your mask. - What?
不要碰口罩
Do not touch your mask.
托尼你知道我不会伤害你请站过姊
Tony, you know I'm not gonna hurt you. Stand here, pleas
好吗我需要你集中精神看着我
OK? I need your concentration. Look at me.
起手套
Pinch your glove...
没错然后下来
That's right...and pull.
对两根手指伸进去
OK. Two fingers underneath,
然后推
and push.
扔到这里洗洗手
And here, wash your hands.
扔到这里 洗洗手
扔到这里洗洗手
And here, wash your hands.
肯尼会好起来吗
Is Kenny gonna be OK?
我觉得会的
I think so, yeah.
快点托尼认真洗
Come on, Tony, wash them properly.
-为什么凶我-我没有凶
- Why are you shouting at me? - I'm not shouting.
再洗一次
And again.
你为什么这么区
Why are you shouting?
我只是生自己的气
I'm just angry with myself, that's all.
-你没有生我的气吧-没有
- You're not angry at me, are you? - No.
好了
There we go.
现在我们可以把口罩摘下来了看着手
Now we can take our masks off. Look at me.
好的你可以把你的摘下来我
OK. You can take yours off, and l'll...
我换一个
...I'll swap mine.
好了托尼我现在需要你做的是
OK, Tony, what I need you to do now, right,
我需要你脱下所有的衣服
is I need you to take all your clothes off
我会拿去洗
and I'm gonna take them to be washed.
行不过这样你就把我看光光了
Yeah, but you'll see me naked, though.
然后你需要冲个澡
And then I need you to get in the shower.
-我很快回来 -好的
- Be back in one minute....- OK.
我帮你拿几件干净衣服托尼
I'm gonna get you some clean clothes, Tony.
水可以关了
You can turn that off now.
你自己穿衣服可以吗
Can you get yourself dressed?
-好的-我把要换的睡衣放在这了
- Yeah. - I've got you some new pyjamas there.
谢谢你亲爱的
Thanks, love.
先擦干 再穿衣服 好吗
Well, get dry first, eh?
OK.
现在几点了
What time is it?
三点半
Oh, it's 3:30.
我觉得很累
好
I feel quite tired.
嗯我也是
Yeah, me, too.
今晚谢谢你了
Thank you for tonight.
我什么都没帮上
Well, I didn't do anything.
不你是我的英雄
No, you're me hero.
有些时候我感觉还可以你知道吗
Some days I feel OK, you know?
的日子里我感觉自己很清醒知道自己应该是什么
Some days I feel like l'm aware, and what I should be.
还有些日子里我都不知道自己在哪
And then some days I don't know where the fuck I am!
但如果我帮上忙了 那就太好了
But if I helped, you know, that's nice.
可以登录国家医疗服务网站111.nhs.uk
.available online through the NHS website, 111.nhs.uk.
若您不需要来自
In cases where you think emergency advice
临床专家的紧急建议
from a clinical expert is not required,
您可以在国家医疗服务网站上查看自疗建议
you can find advice on self treatment on the NHS website.
您也可以考虑听取药房
You may also want to consider getting advice
和社区医生的建议
from your pharmacy or GP.
您可以在网上找到新冠肺炎 感冒 流感的医疗建议
You can find advice online on coronavirus and cold and flu...
请您留意多数患新冠肺炎的病人
Please take into consideration that most patients
可能只表现出轻微的症状
suffering from coronavirus may only display minor symptoms
这些病人需要的治疗
and only require the same treatment
与寻常感冒 流感没有差别
as the normal cold and flu symptoms.
但是如果您有新冠症状
However, if you are displaying the symptoms,
您必须采取措施自我隔离 保护他人
you must also take measures to self isolate and protect others.
对于那些没有得到特别建议的病人
For patients who have not been specifically advised to seek advice,
只有您的症状极大限制了
you should only seek further assistance
日常活动的能力
if your symptoms are significantly limiting your capacity
您才需要寻求进一步帮助
to continue with everyday activities.
如果您现在处于这种状况 且仍需要咨询
If this is the case and you still require consultation,
你要先出来吗
Do you want to come outside?
昨晚只有你一个人在吗
We were on your own here last night?
我连着倒了两班你知道吗
Yeah, I ended up doing a double, you know?
我得去把早饭养好
I need to get the breakfast together.
你刚上了20小时的班
You've just done a 20 hour shift.
肯尼状况不好 还有
Kenny's not well... and...
你为什么让他趴着
Why did you put him on his front?
网上说这样能让他舒服一点
Well, they said to make and comfortable, and..
所以你就想自作主张了
So you thought you'd go rogue.
我很佩服你的勇气
I admire the balls.
就好像把我们忘了一样 不是吗
Yeah, it's like they've forgot about us, isn't it?
回家去吧 我来做故早饭
Get yourself home. I'll do the breakfast.
今天是4月21日星期二 欢迎收听《今日新闻》
This is Today at seven o'clock on Tuesday, 21st of April.
代表英国国家医疗服务信托的机构
The body which represents NHS trusts in England
警告公众不要戴口罩
has warned against advising the public to wear masks,
其表示这可能会导致在新冠病毒流行期间
saying it could jeopardise supplies for health workers
医务工作者缺少物资
during the coronavirus pandemic.
嗨莎拉我是托莉
Hiya, Sarah, it's Tori.
嗨莎拉我是莉
嗨莎拉我是托莉
Hiya, Sarah, it's Tori.
嗨莎拉我是莉
嗨莎拉我是托莉
Hiya, Sarah, it's Tori.
嗨莎拉我是托新
嗨莎拉我是托莉
Hiya, Sarah, it's Tori.
我觉得应该告诉你 肯尼五分钟之前去世了
I thought that you should know that Kenny passed five minutes ago.
-你给他孩子打电话了吗-没有那是斯蒂夫的活
- Have you called his lad? - No. That's Steve's job.
斯蒂夫病了你也知道之前是我暗着他所以
Well, Steve's sick, and, you know, I was with him, so...
好我有他的电话
Yeah, I've got, erm...his mobile.
我给你做点早饭吗
Can I get you some breakfast?
不用能让我一个人待会儿吗
No. Can you leave me alone?
我看你已经放好彩旗了你回来了
- See you've laid out the bunting, then.... - Oh, you're back.
我看你已经放好彩旗了-你回来了
我看你已经放好彩旗了 -你回来了
- See you've laid out the bunting, then.... - Oh, you're back.
我看你已经放好彩旗了-你回来了
我看你已经放好彩旗了你回来了
- See you've laid out the bunting, then.... - Oh, you're back.
我看你已经放好彩旗了 -你回来了
- See you've laid out the bunting, then... - Oh, you're back.
我回来了 亲爱的
Oh, I'm back, baby.
我搞到了一些不错的防护设备
I've got some fine-looking PPE.
好防护衣好口罩 好手套
Proper aprons, good masks, great gloves.
全都是从中国直接送来的不用我多说了吧
All delivered from China to my door, say no more.
你们看起来都很憔焦悴啊
You both look shattered.
现在是我该说谢谢了吗
Is this the point where I say thank you?
感觉好像现在是这个时机
It feels like this should be that point.
所以现在有什么要做的吗
So, what needs doing?
我们的药物供应眼不上
We're behind on meds.
那么告诉我去曼德勒[缅甸的城市]的路
Then show me the way to Mandalay.
现在我回来管事了
I've come to take charge now.
我之前想了很多
Been doing a lot of thinking.
-我们需要轮流使用外部空间-好主意
- We need a rotation on the use of outside space.... - Good idea.
还有内部空间住户不能总是整天待在屋里
And inside. They can't be in their rooms all day....
好主意我们需要安排访客制度
- Good idea. - We need the system for visits.
只需要在停车场布置一下我们就能..
OOO
I think with some simple rigging in the car park, we'll be...
行小聪明别把我的活都抢了好吗
All right, bright spark, let me get my feet under the table, will you?
CAME
我来给你换床具
I've come to change your bedding.
然后我们来吃早饭好吗
And then let's get you some breakfast, shall we?
托尼吃了什么药
What's Tony on?
一你什么意思你让托尼吃了什么药
- What do you mean? - What the fuck have you put Tony on?
-处方是 -好但是为什么
- It's prescribed.... - Yeah, but why?
莎拉 我知道你对这一切还不太熟悉
Sarah, I know you're still quite new to this
而且之前你的工作很艰难
and you've had a very hard time...
放屁如果你要给他下药那就滚回家去
No, fuck off back home if you're just going to drug him!
他又想逃走
He tried to escape again.
冶终存在潜逃风险所以我们和麦卡维医生谈了
He's a constant flight risk, so we spoke with Dr McCavitt
托尼重新制定了一份治疗计划我们只需要看着
- and devised a new patient plan for Tony.... - We just need to watch him.
我们以前都是看着他就好
We've always watched him before.
他脑子还清醒着斯蒂夫
brain is still good, Steve.
我们不能这么做我以前见过你这种情况
- Can't be doing this. - I've seen this before.
他们不是病人他们是住户
They're not patients, they are residents.
而且大多数人都快死了
And they're mostly fucking dead.
当他需要用脑时却在让他脑子变園
You are slowing him down when he needs his wits about him.
他脑子很正常斯蒂夫
He's got a good head on him, Steve.
他脑子很正常斯蒂失
你别管他就好了
You just leave him be.
你干这一行才干了多久五个月
You've been doing this, what, five months.
我已经在这一行坚持了很公了
I've been pushing this rock up a hill for a little bit longer,
所以注意你的态度等你.
so watch out till you...
所以注意你的态度等你.。
求你了别喂他吃药了多说无益
Please, take him off the drugs, no more needs to be said.
为什么他对你这么重要
Why does he matter so much to you, eh?
因为他是个好人
Because he is a good man.
好人真的太少了
Which is really fucking rare.
我就是坏人了是吗
And I'm a bad man, am l?
我相信你很在乎他们斯蒂夫
I believe you care about them, Steve.
真的
I really do.
T really do.
这不是你的错
And none of this is your fault.
但你执行了你就跟他们那些人一样
But you do this, and you are just like the rest of them.
一你太累了-对确实
- You're exhausted. - Yeah, I am, actually.
疗养院一两周没你也能顶得住所以回家去吧
And the home can cope without you for a week or two, so go home,
好好休息
have a rest,
-好好想想这是不是你想要的结果要炒了我吗
- have a good think about whether this is what you want. - Sacking me?
不是我只是让你知道
No, I'm simply letting you know
我们收入也少了-收入减少是因为他们死了斯蒂
- we have reduced income. - They are reduced cos they died, Steve.
我们收入也少了收入减少是因为他们死了斯蒂:
we have reduced income. - They are reduced cos they died, Steve.
对我就是要让这地方
Yeah, and I'm trying to keep this fucking place
等你好好考虑一下现在的处境
Finish your shift and then give me a call
改变想法后再给我打电话好吗
when you had a little bit of think about the situation, will you?
-好把你口罩戴上
IN ITE
- Yeah.... - Put your mask back on.
只有我一个人 保罗
Only me, Paul.
我不会把你留在这里的
I'm not leaving you in here.
在这里等着托尼
Wait there, Tony.
你确定我在学校什么也没学到吗
Are you sure I didn't learn anything in school, eh?
你能听到鸟叫吗能
·Can you hear the birds? - Yeah.
-*高*-不玩了 太逊了
- *High..*. - No, it's crap.
这首歌太逊了 小美女 我想到首更好听的
It's crap, you soft tomato. I've got a better one.
那可不是首拍手歌
That's not a clap routine!
*当红军行军时*
*Oh, when the Reds go marching in!*
*我想加入他们的行列*
*I want to be in their number*
*当红军行军时*
*Oh, when the Reds go marching in*
一*行军时* -小点声
- *Go marching in...* - Shush!
-小点声 -*当红军行军时*
- Shush! - *When the Reds go marching in...*
那里就是你的天堂
There's your paradise.
也不是很差劲 对吧
It's not so bad, is it?
你只是指今天对吧
You only asked today.
没人喜欢全知全能的人
No-one likes a know-it-all, you know?
小托
Tone!
我得回我妈妈家了
I've got to get back to me ma.
不那是我妈妈听着她需要我
No, it's me ma. Look, she needs me.
我不在家她会担心我的
She worries about me when l'm not there.
你有点迷路了走吧 她家在这边
Hey, you're a little bit lost. Come on now. She's this way.
你那样洗会让我的衣服掉色的
You'll make the colour run on me top like that.
这样一来你就不会像大象一样臭了
That will stop you smelling like an elephant.
下午好欢迎来到唐宁街
Good afternoon and welcome to Downing Street
参加每日新冠疫情简报会
for the daily coronavirus briefing.
我想告诉各位我们在这场危机中
I want to tell you what we've been doing
致力于保护疗养院住户的举措
to protect people in care homes throughout the crisis.
很明显从一开始
Right from the start it's been clear
这种可怕的病毒对老年人的影响最大
that this horrible virus affects older people most.
因此 从一开始我们就试着
So, right from the start we've tried
在疗养院周围建立保护圈
to throw a protective ring around our care homes.
我们于二月发布了第一条通告
We set out our first advice in February
随着病毒的延我们始终都在加强保护
and as the virus grew, we strengthened it throughout.
我们确保疗养院有所需的资源
We made sure that care homes have the resources they need
来控制疫情的蔓延
to control the spread of infection.
社会关怀是一个基层问题..
Social care is a devolved matter...
我以前总说你不会做黄油烤面包
I've always said you can't beat bread and butter.
爸爸 你怎么来这里了
Dad, you can get out of here.
-别这么吃惊.. -不是我认真的
- Now, don't get dramatic.... - Nah, I mean it.
我认真的爸爸快回去
I mean it, Dad, just go.
-你成了封面女郎了 你知道吗 -什么
- You're quite the cover girl, do you know that? - What?
上周你还是《回声》的头版
Well, front page of the Echo you were last week.
"新冠疫情中的亡命鸳鸯"
"Covid on the run."
你以为你能对我指手画脚吗
You think you're the one who's going to fuck it up for me?
我记得奶奶带你来这里拖车旅行过
I remembered Nana took you caravanning round here once.
一你把拖车的锁给撬了吗 -求你了回去吧
- Did you break into the vans? - Go away. Please.
-回去吧 -你他妈的总爱作妖
- Please go away. - Always with the fucking drama!
这是别人度假住的地方 别人的梦想啊
These are people's holidays, people's dreams.
我们已经隔离了十天了
We've done ten days.
只要再隔离四天就够了
We only need to do four more....
我们只需坚持14天
We just need to get to 14 days
然后我会要求他们重新安置他
and then l'll make them put him somewhere different.
14天只要14天就行了不是吗
Well, for 14 days, that's all that matters, isn't it?
他们会知道他没有得病然后我觉得
You know, they'll know he doesn't have it, then, and I think...
我觉得他就能获准离开
I'm sure he will be allowed to go...
他就会获准去个不一样的地方
He'll be allowed to go somewhere different.
-你总是这么说 -因为你他妈的就是
- You always say that. - Because you fucking are!
疫情开始之前我们有20个住户
We had 20 residents when this started.
爸爸他们在一个一个地死去 一个接一个
They've been dying off, one by one, Dad.
一想到放任他待在那里
The thought of leaving him like that...
不食物就寻常吃的就行
No...Uh, food. Just normal food.
一怎么了 -右脚噢 就这样
- What's going on? - Right foot. Ooh! There you go.
再下左脚 下一步完美
Left foot down. Next step. Perfect.
别太期待哦
Don't get your hopes up, all right?
但还行你明白我的意思吗
But it's something, do you know what I mean?
你要带我去哪里 去枪毙还是什么
Where are you taking me? To the firing squad or something?
你知道怎么玩傻蛋纸牌吗
Do you know how to play shitter?
这是给我的惊喜吗
Is this me surprise?
你知道吗 我以前没怎么出过远门
Do you know? I've never done much of this before.
一想到我们熟知的世界 就没兴致了
To think the world we know and it's all over.
免轮班只为了一件事,0
Shift-free for one thing.
我小时候出去度过假
We went on holiday when I was a kid.
-峨多尼哥-对多尼哥
- Oh, Donegal... - Donegal. Yeah.
我妈妈有个堂姐
Yeah, me ma had a cousin.
她死后留给了我们点钱
Left us some money when she died
然后她突发奇想"管他的我们要去多尼哥"
and she just went, "Fuck it. We're going to Donegal."
直到今天我都不清楚为什么是多尼哥
To this day, I don't know why it was Donegal.
你们是跟特丽莎一起去的-对
- Were you there with Trish? - Yeah.
其实你看上去有点像她 。
You look like her a little bit, actually.
我总是能看出别人的温柔
Can always tell when someone's a bit soft.
我不温柔我不温柔
I'm not soft. I'm not soft!
一你很温柔-好吧
- You're soft... - Oh, right.
-对我知道-是啊
- Yeah, I know.... - Yeah.
不过你是蓝鼻子
Yeah, you're a blue, though.
一你是埃弗顿你是埃弗顿 -不是
- You're Everton. You're Everton. - Nah!
然后呢你是怎么知道的
And what? How did you know that?
-你是怎么知道的一因为我可以间到
- How did you know that? - Because I can smell it.
-我以为我骗到你了一你才没有
- I thought I had you.... - No, you didn't.
不过没有让我讨庆你
Hasn't put me off you, though.
等下你们能不能
Look, can you just...?
-就等一下-亲爱的现在就走
- Just wait for one minute. - Come on now, love.
-亲爱的现在就走过来-不不
- Come on now, love. Come here.... - No! No!
不你们不能不不能这样
No, you don't. No, you don't.
你们要带她去哪里
Where are you taking her?
你需要跟我走一趟
You're going to come with me for a minute.
我不想跟你走我想跟莎拉一起走
I don't want to go with you. I want to go with Sarah.
你可以不说话
You do not have to say anything.
但如果你被讯问时不表态
Harm your defence
将会不利于你日后在法庭上依据这件事
if you do not mention when questioned something
你所说的任何话都可能作为证据
Anything you do say may be given in evidence.
-听懂我的话了吗-请不要把他带回去
- Do you understand me? - Please don't take him back there.
-你不明白 -莎拉
- You don't understand.... - Sarah,
亲爱的你的麻频已经够多了-求你了
- you're in enough trouble as it is, love.... - Please.
-冷静莎拉来
- Calm down. - Come on, Sarah.
莎拉不我要跟莎拉一起
Sarah. No, I'm going with Sarah.
是我爸爸告诉你的
Was it me dad who told you?
不是几个步行者看到了你好心人啊
No, some walkers saw you. Do-gooders, you know.
多亏他们帮忙才抓到你
Well, they did good. Caught you.
我需要你的帮助 请听我说
I need your help. Listen to me.
他已经隔离了12天
He's done 12 days.
一他几乎很安全了不行
- He's nearly safe.... - No.
是我带他来隔离的-不行
- No, I quarantined him, I did.... - No.
就用一下无线电 跟他们说别把他带回去
Just radio in and tell them not to take him back there.
带他去别的地方求你了
Take him somewhere else, please.
求你了一你在听我说活吗
- Please! - Are you listening to me?
一你在听我说吗。求你了
- Are you listening to me? - Please
-求你了一亲爱的 那不是我的部门
- Please.... - It's not my department, love.
不不不永远都是不
No. No. No, it never is, is it? Eh?
不永远都是不永远都是不
No, never...Never is. Never is.
这个国家就是这么运转的
It's the way this country works now.
低个头看看那些被抛弃的人啊
You know, keep our eyes down to the rest of it.
我们这种人看到饥饿的人排队领食物
You know, cos if we see people queueing up for food banks
看到流浪的人躺在 躺在大街上
and if we see people lying...Lying on the streets,
看到被抛弃的残疾人只能等死至少还有愧疚
if we see disabled people being left to die, we'll feel sorry.
我们过不下去了有托利党我们过不下去
We can't cope. We can't cope with Tory. Not us.
从什么时候起我们的生命不再平等了
When did our lives stop being worth the same, eh?
你现在无须担心她
You don't need to worry about her right now.
来 先进来喝一杯好茶
Come on. Let's just get you in. Have a nice cup of tea.